=Royal Upstart 2=
(Based on "Zhenguan Foolish Son-in-Law")
=Episode 25=
(The Power of Movable Type)
Wei the Fool.
Why don't you come in?
My mother said
you don't need to be announced.
Here.
I'm not cold.
Girl,
(By Wei Hao)
this is a memorial to the Emperor.
Keep it safe.
A memorial?
Shouldn't that be given to my father?
Listen closely.
You must hide this memorial well.
No one can know about it.
If I am killed by the great clans,
please give this to your father.
Do you understand?
Fool,
don't scare me like that.
I'm about to go head-to-head
with the great clans, right?
They won't let me off easily.
If I win, everything will be fine.
I'm just afraid
they'll do something desperate,
so I'm giving this memorial to you first.
It's okay.
Those great clans
won't dare touch me.
If something really happens to me,
your father won't
let them get away with it.
I'm just thinking
that we should have a backup plan.
Girl,
remember what I said.
If anything happens to me,
give it to your father.
Until then,
no one can know
that I've left a memorial with you.
I'll remember.
Wei Hao,
if you're in danger,
then forget it.
I won't marry anyone else.
I'll just wait in the Princess Mansion.
At worst,
we'll just be together
for life without a title.
I'm willing to do that for you.
What nonsense is that?
I'm going to marry you properly.
Why would we be together without titles?
Girl,
as long as you're willing to marry me,
even if the whole world is against it,
nothing can stop me from marrying you.
To heck with those great clans.
They're just a bunch of clowns.
Don't worry.
Hide this memorial well.
And tell my mother-in-law as well.
Tell her to wait for my good news.
What does this Wei Hao think he's doing?
Making us wait for him this long?
He should be here soon.
He's coming.
Is Wei the Fool really that difficult?
Father,
you'll understand once you see him.
Ridiculous!
To think that one man
could reduce the lot of you
to such a pathetic state.
Aren't you ashamed of yourselves?
Clan Leader,
Wei Hao is here.
He's here.
You're all here.
How about I treat you to this meal?
Forget it.
It will be my treat.
Later,
make your situation clear.
It's best to call your engagement off.
Fine.
Should we talk first,
or eat first?
I suggest we eat first.
I'm afraid you won't
have an appetite later,
and that would be a waste.
Wei Hao,
stop trying to intimidate us.
If you don't call off the engagement,
you're effectively
throwing your peerage away, right?
Clan Leader Wei,
if Wei Hao refuses to obey
your orders as clan leader,
can't you just expel him from your clan?
Wei Hao,
listen to me and call off this marriage.
I'll find you
a much better match.
How about that?
The other clan leaders here
all have daughters and granddaughters.
You're a Marquis now.
Take your pick.
Why must you cause such a massive scene?
Clan Leader,
I only like Ning'an.
I only like the Eldest Princess.
What can I do?
Did Wei Hao
tell you
what method
he'll use against those clan heads?
(Wei Hao said)
(to keep the memorial secret.)
No.
He just told me not to worry
and to leave it to him.
(Where does he get this confidence?)
Brat,
what's all this nonsense about love?
Come on.
Listen to me.
I wouldn't steer you wrong.
I'm not listening.
It seems that if we don't clear this up,
no one will have the appetite to eat.
Then, let's settle this first.
(The Analects)
What...
What is this?
Wei Hao,
what are you trying to do?
(Learning and practicing it regularly,
isn't that a joy?)
(The Analects)
What is this for?
(Master said: "Learning and practicing
it regularly, isn't that a joy?")
(Having friends come from far away,
isn't that happiness?)
(Is that not...)
(People of this era)
(Gentleman)
(clearly don't understand the principle of a puzzle.)
(Otherwise, woodblock printing)
(would have evolved
into movable type long ago.)
(Having friends come from far away,
isn't that happiness?)
Just playing tricks.
(Since that's the case,)
(I'll give you all)
(the visual shock of movable type.)
(Is this)
(rubbing?)
(A gentleman focuses on the roots.
Once rooted, the Way grows.)
(Are filial piety and fraternal respect
not the roots of benevolence?)
This...
(A gentleman focuses on the roots.
Once rooted, the Way grows.)
This...
Help me check this.
Are there any typos?
Quick, take a look.
This...
Hurry.
(How can he print things)
(using such simple tools?)
This...
(This...)
(Is he assembling the woodblock
for the second page.)
(Happiness)
(A joy?)
(Learning and...)
(With just these few characters,)
(is he going to assemble
the woodblocks for the entire book?)
(A joy?
Having friends come from far away)
(It's over.)
(Not resenting when others don't
understand you, isn't that a gentleman?)
This...
Help me take a look.
Did I print
the first two pages correctly?
This... Father...
This is...
This...
You keep moving these around...
What to do now?
And you can print a whole book?
Come.
Pick the characters.
I will let you print
the third page.
No, thanks.
Just give it a try.
No...
What I said before
about selling 100,000 books a month
was a modest estimate.
This...
Let me tell you,
at the very least,
one million books a month.
This...
I can print a hundred
different books at the same time.
This...
I guarantee
that from today onward,
all the scholars in the world
will never lack books again.
(This is bad.)
(This is disastrous.)
(This thing could actually
destroy the great clans.)
Clan Leader Cui,
why don't
you come try it?
Come on!
(I never would have thought)
(that Wei the Fool
actually knew how to do this.)
(Now that he has this,)
(the Emperor can destroy
the great clans whenever he wants.)
(We cannot let
the Emperor find out about this.)
(Otherwise, it's the end
for the great clans.)
Wei Hao,
put it away.
Let's
have a proper talk.
Yes.
Let's have a proper talk.
You want to talk?
Fine.
Pack it up.
Go.
On the 22nd,
for my engagement banquet with Ning'an,
be there on time.
(Invitation)
(The 22nd of this month, respectfully
from Wei Hao and Wei Ning'an)
Are you coming or not? Say something!
We'll come.
Don't you worry.
We'll be there.
Yes, we'll come.
We will be there.
Good.
Now, let's talk.
How are you going to
compensate me for this?
If I release this thing,
it'll make at least 30,000 guan a month.
So, what's your final word?
Shall I release it or not?
Of course, you shouldn't release it.
Right...
Clan Leader Wei,
persuade your young kinsman.
Ask him not to be impulsive.
Exactly.
Wei Hao,
don't be impulsive.
You see,
we don't oppose your marriage
to the Eldest Princess.
In fact, we will give you our blessings.
It's just that...
It would be best
to destroy the thing.
Forever.
It's better
if it never appears in the world.
Let's talk first.
If you want to talk,
then show some sincerity.
How about you set your conditions,
and we'll discuss them?
What do you say?
Fine.
In that case, I won't hold back.
I'll give you two choices.
First,
each clan gives me
10,000 guan every year
until the day I die.
Second,
let me recruit 500 students
from humble backgrounds every year.
I will train them.
How...
How can that be acceptable?
You want to train
500 scholars for His Majesty
to be used against us?
Do it now.
♪Everyone says I'm a big silly fool♪
♪When things happen,
I only know how to count on my fingers♪
♪They shake their heads
and say I'm pitiful♪
♪Sigh and walk away♪
♪Little do they know,
I am sharp and bright♪
♪With a heart like a mirror,
I understand the world's♪
♪Colors and darkness♪
♪But I keep my edge hidden♪
♪The day I become famous
is just around the corner♪
♪In the hotpot restaurant,
skewers boil in the broth♪
♪People come and go,
with few worries or troubles♪
♪The clacking of the abacus rings out♪
♪See me differently.
Who dares to challenge me?♪
♪The world mistakes me♪
♪For an ignorant and stubborn fool♪
♪As the storm approaches♪
♪I just shrug and watch with a smile♪
♪This foolish image is convenient♪
♪I use it as a protective shield♪
♪Navigating with ease, I attract♪
♪A lucky star to accompany me♪
♪In a peaceful golden age♪
♪I hold my lady's hand
to watch the world♪
♪Pouring youth and fireworks♪
♪Into a precious glazed cup♪
♪Having experienced life's changes♪
♪And tasted its highs and lows♪
♪My wish has finally come true♪
♪To stay by your side♪
♪In this fleeting world♪
♪We are free and happy♪
♪From a nobody♪
♪To someone now famous♪
♪Ordinary people laugh at me♪
♪But I laugh at how
they cannot see through it all♪
♪Let others plot and scheme♪
♪I will keep my heart unchanged♪
♪In this vast world♪
♪I find my own leisurely freedom♪
♪The world is bustling,
and things constantly change♪
♪Everything ends eventually♪
♪All that remains before my eyes♪
♪Is this street wandering,
still tinged with pity♪
♪No matter how time flies♪
♪Even if the falling snow♪
♪Dyes the hair at our temples white♪
♪All I want now♪
♪Is to pray for
my lady's peace and safety♪
♪Year after year♪